Mason Choi

Contact

Objective

201 West Brookline Street, Boston, MA, 02118 (617) 875-1803 I am a passionate and motivated student who has been working professionally as a data engineer for over a year and has worked on projects that have saved my company hundreds of hours of time. I have also worked on many of my own successful projects and business, pursued higher education than what my high school could provide, and am a highly skilled competitive fencer.

choi.mason@gmail.com

Education

Experience

Boston Latin School GPA: 4.3 of 4.38 SAT: 1550 (760 Verbal 790 Math) September 2022 – Present Junior Data Engineer • Solve Advisors Inc.

Computer Science club Model United Nations Recycling club March 2022 – September 2022 Developer/Analyst • Solve Advisors Inc.

September 2021 – March 2022

Junior Data Engineer • Advantage Data Inc. + Best Credit Management Inc.

I have developed data pipelines following the Extract Transform Load paradigm for two separate Fintech companies. I played a major role in building data collection and manipulation tools and collaborated heavily with different teams on various industry revolutionizing projects.

Key Skills

Extracurriculars

Communicative
Hard working
Leader
Flexible

Fencing Individual – I fence at both the highest national level and regionally travelling across the country just about every other week. I currently rank 38th in the country for U17 Men's Epee, 2nd in the region and 4th for U19. I expect to compete internationally on the U.S. World team this season.

Languages: English – Native Chinese – Proficient Latin – Proficient Korean - Elementary Fencing Varsity – I have brought the BLS fencing team to the state championships every year I competed and have been qualified for Varsity leadership since 7th grade.

Community Service – Service is very important to me, which is why I have been volunteering with the Homeless Outreach Ministry and Engagement (HOME) team as one of the longest serving members feeding and engaging with homeless people of Boston. I have over 70 confirmed hours of community service, but that is just the beginning.

Technology Stack

Notable Academic Achievement

Fluent languages: Python, Java, HTML/CSS, SQL Libraries: Tensorflow, Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib Frameworks: React, Flask, Django, React Native Tools: AWS, MS/G suite, Git, GitHub Principles of Big Data Processing (CSCI E-88, graduate) • Harvard Extension School • Projected Final Grade: 100% • Credits: 4

Statistics 111 • University of Massachusetts Amherst • Final Grade: 98.80% • Credits: 4

Computer Science 121 • University of Massachusetts Amherst • Final Grade: 100.00% • Credits: 4

Calculus I • University of Pittsburgh • Final Grade: 99.00% • Credits: 3

Links

Approbation with Distinction every term for above A- in every class Summa Cum Laude 3 years in a row on the National Latin Exam

Personal Website: https://masonchoi.net

USACO Silver on first attempt, I expect a Gold or Platinum promotion this season